ADESIJI BLESSING ADETOYE

Mobile: +234 8143951456 | Email: blessingadesiji96@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/bleso-a | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bdetoye/

Website: https://bleso-a.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

An impact-driven individual who is adept in web development, data science, machine learning and analytics. Experienced in undertaking complex projects in these areas; data analytics, visualizations, developing machine learning models, web development.

Working knowledge of the following languages & tools: Python, Golang, R, JavaScript, Swift, HTML, CSS, Power BI, Excel, SQL, Spark, NoSQL, & Cloud Services(AWS, GCP, Azure).

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

•	Bachelor of Science, Petroleum Engineering – University of Ibadan, Ibadan	2015 – 2019
	Degree: Second Class Upper Honours (CGPA: 5.8/7.0)	
•	Cambridge Advanced Level GCE- University of Cambridge	2013- 2014
	Physics(A*), Mathematics(A), Chemistry(A)	
•	Intro to Cloud Computing- Udacity.com	June 2020
•	Data Engineering Nanodegree – Udacity.com	June 2020
•	Web Development Pathway – Codecademy.com	March- June 2020
•	Python REST APIs with Flask, Docker, MongoDB & AWS DevOps – Udemy.com	May 2020
•	Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals- Coursera.org	April 2020
•	Microsoft Professional Data Science Certification – Microsoft/DataHack4Fl	April 2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ustacky - Data Scientist cum Technical Content Director

July 2020 - Till Date

- Developed curriculum for Data Science & Engineering subjects, including Structured Query Language(SQL), Data Analysis with Pandas,
 & Machine Learning topics.
- Strategize and teach courses in data-related microdegree programs.
- Collaborate with a diverse team of engineers, managers to develop an e-learning platform.

Udacity - Mentor & Project Reviewer

July 2020 - Till Date

 Mentoring students worldwide enrolled in Udacity's Nanodegree program by providing them with constructive feedback on the following courses; Machine Learning Engineer with Microsoft Azure and Digital Marketing (Conquer the Freelance Market).

Smarterise Integrated Solutions - Data Scientist

May 2019 - June 2020

- Developed insights dashboard that helps clients understand their business problems and provide solutions.
- Utilizing tools such as Power BI, Python, MongoDB and cloud server to obtain data, and generate meaningful insights.
- Developed an interactive visualization web-apps using Dash, Plotly and flask framework in python.
- Worked with a diverse team of Data Engineers, Software Engineers to develop products for clients.
- Built the company website using Wix and Developer tools (JavaScript) www.smarterise.com

Addax Petroleum Nigeria – Drilling and Completion Engineering Project Management Intern September 2017 – February 2018

- Developed a robust financial tracking application that logs completed rig operations and prompt business services for payment validation.
- Responsible for all drilling department correspondences, well-site/office drilling reports cataloguing, communication with service contractors and minutes of meeting preparation and circulation.
- Interfaced with contractors and clients to support, track, and publish reports of daily Oil Rig concurrent operations.

Global Cambridge College, Ibadan - Physics and Mathematics Student Tutor

April 2014 - March 2015

- Prepared various students for Cambridge Subsidiary & Advanced Level Exams.
- Taught topics in Advanced level Physics & Mathematics Syllabuses.
- Increased the percentage of students that passed the Physics and Mathematics final exams by 30%

PUBLICATION

Akinsete, O., & Adesiji, B. A. (2019, August 5). Bottom-Hole Pressure Estimation from Wellhead Data Using Artificial Neural Network. Society of Petroleum Engineers (NAICE)

Blessing Adesiji (Medium) - Understanding Recursion with Factorial and an English Ruler Drawing.

PROJECTS - Link

- <u>Car Owners Web Application Developed a web application that return car owners using Nodels & Reactls</u>
- Give Your Application Auto-Deploy Superpowers- A Cloud DevOps Project.
- Operationalize Machine Learning Pipeline with Microsoft Azure (AutoML)
- Optimize Machine Learning Pipeline with Microsoft Azure (HyperDrive, Data Factory)
- Data Modeling with Postgres Created a database and ETL pipeline in Postgres for a music streaming app.
- Data Modeling with Apache Cassandra Created a non-relational database and ETL pipeline in Postgres for a music streaming app.
- Data Warehouse (AWS) Built an ETL pipeline that extracts data from S3, stages them in AWS Redshift, and transforms for analytics.
- Developed a Machine Learning Model that predicts loan default by bank customers in Data Science Nigeria Bootcamp.
- Developed a Machine Learning Model that predicted customers' loan default, customer churn rate and propensity to transact for Access Bank Data Hackathon.
- Developed a Machine Learning Model using Artificial Neural Network to determine Oil Wells bottom-hole flowing pressure.
- Developed a model that was used to tutor participants (beginners) in Data Science Artificial Intelligence Invasion program.

LEADERSHIP AND VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Educate an African Child Initiative, University of Ibadan

September 2018 - March 2019

- Volunteered to educate kids living in marginalized communities.
- Assisted to provide mentorship activities and educational training to out-of-school children.

General Secretary, Society of Petroleum Engineers, University of Ibadan

January 2018 - December 2018

- Provided administrative support for the society that included creating reports, letters, and board meeting minutes.
- Supervised Society's important activities such as Oil & Gas Industry Week, Career Orientation Programmes, and Skills development training.

2018 Hult Prize University of Ibadan Intercampus Idea competition Team Leader

November 2018

- Designed an idea that improved learning within the campus by leveraging on an individual with talents in the society.
- Led a team that recorded success in the pitching competition and launched the idea on campus.

AWARDS

•	Ranked 8th in Uber & Mobiticket Predicting People's Movement – Zindi Data Science ML Hackathon.	2019
•	Top participant in Access Bank/ Africa Fintech Foundry/ Data Science Nigeria Hackathon (2018 & 2019).	2018 – 2019
•	Top 10 in Hult Prize Entrepreneurship Idea Competition, University of Ibadan Campus.	2018
•	Ranked 19th amongst 10,000 students in the Data Science Nigeria Intercampus Machine Learning Competition.	2018
•	Received Outstanding Student Chapter Award on behalf of UI, SPE chapter in ATCE, Dubai.	2016
•	Best Graduating Student in Global Cambridge Advanced Level College.	2014

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- HTML & CSS
- Google Cloud Services (Google, AWS, Azure)
- JavaScript
- Golang
- Python
- Deep Learning
- Web development
- Power BI

- Machine Learning
- WordPress
- Data Visualization
- Design thinking
- Strong Work Ethics
- Written communication & Communication Skill
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office Suite